Heiner Andrés Solano Arguedas

+50664040376 Heredia heiner.andres@outlook.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with 5 years working in development, implementation and maintenance of technological solutions. With knowledge of programming languages, databases and operating systems. Demonstrated ability to solve complex problems, optimize processes, and collaborate in multidisciplinary teams. Focused on innovation and continuous improvement, with communication and leadership skills to coordinate teams.

Stacks:

- ✓ <u>Windows</u>, C# Web, Desktop, Apis, WCF, Azure.
- ✓ <u>Web</u>, Angular, NodeJS, React, Django.
- ✓ Mobile, Java, Kotlin.
- ✓ <u>Data bases</u>, Sql, Oracle, Postgresql.
- ✓ Analytics and data science, Python.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Novacomp February 2022 – November 2022

IT Service company specialized in software development, outsourcing and technology consulting, present in more than 23 countries. Novacomp is a technology company that provides software development and IT consulting services to help businesses with their digital transformation.

Software Engineer

- Collaborate with clients, project managers and stakeholders to understand the business needs and technical specifications of the software.
- Work closely with other developers, designers, testers, and project managers using version control tools and agile methodologies like Scrum.
- Write clean, efficient and well-documented code using programming languages.
- Test the software to identify bugs or errors, and fix them to ensure proper functionality and reliability.
- Participate in review teammates code to ensure quality, promote best practices and share knowledge across the team.
- Stay up to date with new tools, frameworks and industry trends to bring innovative solutions to software projects.

Technologies: C#, Windows Forms, WCF, SQLServer, Git, CI/CD pipelines, Azure, TFS.

Grupo Babel October 2020 - February 2022

Multinational technology company, specialized in IT solutions. With presence in 14 countries, Babel focuses on emerging technologies, including generative AI, cybersecurity, hyperautomation, data analytics, and cloud solutions.

Software Engineer

- Understand project needs by gathering and analyzing client and stakeholder requirements to define clear software objectives.
- Participate in agile workflows such as dailys, sprint planning, and retrospectives to align development efforts.
- Develop robust and scalable applications by following best coding practices and design patterns.
- Debug and troubleshoot errors in the codebase, analyzing causes and implementing effective solutions.
- Review teammates code to identify potential issues, suggest improvements and share knowledge.
- Research with new frameworks, languages and methodologies to bring innovations to projects.

Technologies: C#, MVC, Rest Api, SQLServer, Git, CI/CD pipelines, Azure, TFS.

Optimized Data Solutions

August 2016 – January 2018

Outsourcing company that specializes in provide high-quality IT and data services to international clients.

Systems Engineer

Functions:

- Define what the software must do identifying user ideas and aligning them with system capabilities.
- Translate software designs and specifications into functional code that meets project requirements.
- Ensure software behaves as expected by executing test cases, resolving defects and validating user requirements.
- Use version control systems and communication tools to coordinate tasks and share knowledge.
- Maintain a clean and efficient codebase, review processes and collaborative discussions.
- Learn about modern technologies that align with project goals and improve team productivity.

Technologies: C#, MVC, WCF, SQL, TFS.

<u>Seidor</u> March 2015 – Juny 2016

Global technology consulting firm, partner company in businesses improving their operational efficiency, customer experiences, and overall competitiveness, specializes in providing Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), cloud computing, data management, artificial intelligence and cybersecurity.

Systems Engineer

WM technical consulting in a SAP implementation, create a soap service to communicate the ERP and the application that we made after in Android Studio, the app reads barcodes for the movement of products. Technologies: Python, Android Studio, Java, Postgresql.

Python (library to host the program in a Windows process, library to communicate with SAP, library to create a SOAP, installations and configurations).

Android Studio (research to read barcodes, communication with the SOAP, permissions, activities, intents, etc).

Individual projects

Systems Engineer

February 2023 - Present

- 1. Portfolio.
 - React (React Router, Components and Hooks).
 - CSS, responsive design.
 - Version control with Git.
 - CI/CD: Azure App Service deploy.

Web site (May take 2 3 minuts, react downloads the entire app in the browser the first time).

2. Amazon page

- React (React Router, Redux, Components, Hooks, Api integration, Google authentication).
- CSS, responsive design.
- Nodejs (Api creation, database docs and querys)
- Version control with Git.
- CI/CD: Azure App Service deploy.
- Functionality: LogIn, products view, products stock, card management (add, delete or change the number of products, calculate subtotal.

Web site (May take 2 3 minuts, react downloads the entire app in the browser the first time).

EDUCATION

- Universidad Nacional, Heredia, Costa Rica. Information Systems Engineering (2018).
- Invenio-Sykes, San José, Costa Rica. English for employability Program (2020).

CURSES

- UNA, Python Programming for Data Science
- UNA, Apps Development with Android Studio
- **Udemy**, Windows Communication Foundation
- Udemy, Angular, Javascript Jquery, NodeJS
- Udemy, React cero to expert (Hooks y MERN)
- Udemy, IOS & Swift, The complete development Bootcamp
- Udemy, Git curse
- ♣ Hacker Mentor Academy, Cybersecurity